#### **ANTHONY CROUTS**

1202 Rindge Lane • Redondo Beach, CA 90278

Mobile: (310) 343-5939 • Email: acrouts@yahoo.com

#### MANAGEMENT PROFILE

Results driven business executive with over 18 years of consumer product marketing and business development experience in the entertainment, digital content delivery, and gaming industry.

Responsible for branding and marketing campaigns for an expanded range of successful and world renowned entertainment and videogame properties including: EA Sports, FOX Sports, Sony Playstation, Metal Gear Solid, Gran Turismo, Little Big Planet, MapleStory, and X-Men.

A key driver in establishing and maintaining profitable strategic partnerships both domestically and globally, with experience in managing and improving all core business functions and profitability within an organization.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **NEXON (NYSE: NEXOF)**

# **NEXON America**

# **Director of Marketing (October 2012 – Present)**

- Responsible for strategic planning for the entire product portfolio and digital payment infrastructure with full P&L responsibility in a \$4 Billion company, with over \$245MM in yearly transaction volume
- Developed and executed user acquisition initiatives that directly led to a 33% increase in new user acquisition and a 18% reduction in churned users on a constant yearly basis
- Directly responsible for the brand management of the MaplesStory franchise that generates over \$100MM in global revenue
- Manage all existing and potential acquisitions of strategic partnerships with technical integration responsibility
- Expanded digital distribution and payment platforms to that led to an increase of over 20% YOY revenue volume through key partnerships with Amazon, Steam, Incomm, Blackhawk Networks, and PayPal
- Spearheaded strategic B2B initiatives that generating over \$15MM in incremental revenue for FY 2017
- Lead and manage a cross functional team across multiple disciplines including: Brand Marketing, Acquisition Marketing Monetization Strategy, CRM, Data Analytics

# SONY (NYSE: SNE) Sony Playstation

# Director, Product Marketing (February 2010 – October 2012)

- Direct management responsibility for a product portfolio that included several multi-million unit sellers (Gran Turismo, MLB The Show, Little Big Planet) and strategic Hardware platform initiatives with full business plan and P&L responsibility. Generated over \$200MM in revenue.
- Successfully launched "Gran Turismo 5" as the #3 grossing 1<sup>st</sup> party title on the Playstation 3 platform and exceeded business plan objectives by over 40%
- Established strategic product portfolio planning guidelines that incorporated frontline/catalog/bundling pricing and downloadable content release timing that added an incremental 12% gross revenue to the FY business plan
- Established and managed relationships with other Sony divisions (including Sony Network Entertainment, Sony Music, Sony Electronics, Sony Pictures) and identified new creative marketing opportunities and cross-promotional partnerships
- Provided strategic direction and directly worked with the advertising agencies in the development and execution of multiple major platform (PS3, PS Move, PS Portable, PS4) and franchise (MLB the Show, Gran Turismo, Little Big planet, SOCOM 4) TV and Digital campaigns which increased brand awareness and product sell through performance
- Played a key role in the successful launch of the Playstaton Move platform which exceeded Fiscal Year business plan objectives by 120%
- Managed and mentored a team of 12 marketing professionals

# KONAMI DIGITAL ENTERTAINMENT, INC. (NYSE: KNM)

### Vice President of Marketing (June 2007 – December 2009)

- Responsible for the development of strategic marketing planning for all Konami franchises (Full P&L responsibility) in the North America, Latin America, and South America markets. Generated over \$185MM in revenue.
- Led entire re-structuring efforts for Brand Marketing, Promotions, Channel Marketing, Online Marketing, Community Management, Creative Services, Publicity, Customer Support, and Media Planning groups which added new disciplines to the organization and increased performance efficiency
- Orchestrated the largest product launch in Konami's history (Metal Gear Solid 4) with innovative strategies that led to achieving over 150% of the initial forecast generating over \$83MM in gross revenue
- Oversaw new market development, analyzed and developed new markets and market segments; help define products and features necessary to maximize market share
- Developed online strategies to create a unified Konami online presence by incorporating dedicated SEO/SEM initiatives, CRM tactics and activities, improved e-commerce performance, and online advertising
- Established marketing and cross-promotion partnerships with Sony Computer Entertainment of America, Microsoft, Nintendo, Google, Paramount Pictures, Warner Brothers Entertainment, 20<sup>th</sup> Century Fox, Universal Pictures, Sony Pictures, Lionsgate Entertainment, Summit Entertainment and also manage corporate executive relationships with these organizations
- Spearheaded the growth and expansion of Konami branded titles in Latin America and South America that directly led to over 25% year-over-year increase in business revenue

# **NEWS CORPORATION (NASDAQ: NWS)**

Twentieth Century FOX Home Entertainment (November 2004 to June 2007)

Sr. Director of Retail Marketing (August 2005 – June 2007)

Director of Marketing, International (November 2004 - August 2005)

- Developed all tactical marketing plans and creative documents for New release Home Entertainment titles such as (Robots, X-Men, and Night At the Museum) for International markets
- Managed Key accounts (Blockbuster, Hollywood, Netflix) that generated over \$240MM in revenue
- Worked closely with the Interactive marketing group to develop an innovative viral marketing tool, "The FOX Lot"
- Provided home office leadership and support in the coordination of product releases in all international territories outside of North America
- Effectively interfaced with all cross functional groups and provided detailed strategic direction

### ACTIVISION BLIZZARD (OCTOBER 2001 to October 2004) (NASDAQ: ATVI)

Vice President of Global Marketing (February 2004 – November 2004)

Director of Global Marketing (July 2002- February 2004)

Sr. Brand Manager, Global Marketing (October 2001- July 2002)

- Established operational objectives, assignments, and delegation of assignments to effectively manage day-to-day execution of tactics/activities for all marketing programs on a global basis
- Oversaw development and execution of comprehensive marketing strategies, plans and timelines, product positioning, and PR initiatives with full P&L responsibility for multi-million dollar budgets across multiple brands/franchises such as: Empire Earth, Tribes, Leisure Suit Larry, Baldur's Gate, Icewind Dale, and SWAT
- Insured brand integrity across multiple internal brands and interfaced with co-publishing and strategic partners such as Interplay Entertainment, Nokia, Sony, Microsoft, and Nintendo
- Provided input and detailed evaluation analysis to business development in evaluating the viability of potential titles/brands and business opportunities that led to over \$100MM+ in gross business plan revenue generation
- Effectively interfaced with the sales group to establish pricing strategies, portfolio management, forecasts, launch timelines, and retail specific promotional programs

# NEWS CORPORATION (MARCH 1998 to OCTOBER 2001) (NASDAQ: NWS)

# FOXSPORTS.com, FOXNEWS.com, FOX.com

## Director of Marketing (April 2000- October 2001)

- Developed tactical marketing plans to grow FOXSPORTS.com to the #2 Sports destination on the internet and played an integral role in setting News Corp's overall marketing strategy
- Worked closely with Strategic Alliances & Business Development in Identifying and evaluating potential key strategic partners for content distribution and offerings
- Managed key strategic relationships with internal and external operating entities and divisional partners including, News Corp., avantgo.com, Fox Sports/Fox Sports Net TV, 20<sup>th</sup> Century Fox Home Entertainment, Harper Collins, L.A. Dodgers, L.A. Lakers, L.A. Kings, Portland Trailblazers, and Dallas Stars
- Worked closely with E-Commerce division to launch the effective and profitable FOXSPORTS.com online store that was
  profitable in its first month of operation exceeding fiscal projections
- Oversaw all promotional plans and managed staff in the execution of all promotions for FOXSPORTS.com, foxnews.com, and fox.com

#### FOX SPORTS INTERACTIVE

## Director of Global Product Marketing (October 1999 - April 2000)

### Brand Manager, Global Sports Marketing (March 1998 - October 1999)

- Responsible for product marketing activity for all Fox Sports Interactive titles domestically and worldwide with full P&L
  responsibility and providing leadership, guidance, and assistance to senior executive staff as well as managing a staff of
  marketing professionals
- Launched the first Fox Sports videogame brand and played a key role in obtaining all major sports licenses (NBA, NFL, NFLPA, MLB, MLBPA, NHL, and NCAA) while managing key strategic relationships
- Developed strategic positioning, creative direction, and managed execution of marketing plans for all titles including directing media buys for trade and consumer audiences
- Conceptualized and executed marketing plans for all titles and presented brand to retail to achieve mass key account placement support at launch (Gamestop, Wal-Mart, Target, and Best Buy)
- Utilized consumer insights implemented new business opportunities and integrated new features sets for PC and video game console products (Nintendo/Playstation) while working closely with product development to insure products were on strategy with positioning and would be competitive in the market

#### **ELECTRONIC ARTS (NASDAQ: ERTS)**

# Associate Product Manager (June 1997-March 1998)

- Responsible for executing all marketing activities for the Madden NFL football videogame (the #1 selling sports title in videogame in history) across multiple platforms
- Developed product positioning creative direction for product launches, packaging, documentation, advertising, Public Relations promotions and sales support materials for NCAA Football and Madden franchises
- Managed relationships with the NFL, NFLPA, NCAA, and the Collegiate Licensing Company to promote and ensure compliance with licensing agreements

### Online Marketing Manager (November 1994 - March 1997)

- Launched the first dedicated EA Sports Website covering all sports franchises
- Worked closely with internal sales team to develop Electronic Arts' first online store

#### **EDUCATION**

#### University of California at Berkeley

Bachelor of Arts degree

#### **Stanford University**

Executive Education, Strategic Marketing Management